好,欢迎回来.
Okay, welcome back.
今天我们将讨论与Shell相关的两个重要主题.
Today we're gonna cover kind of a couple separate like two main topics related to the Shell.
首先,我们将编写一些Shell脚本,主要用bash,
First, we're gonna do some kind of Shell scripting, mainly related to bash,
bash是Mac或Linux系统中默认的Shell.
which is the Shell that most of you will start like in Mac, \N or like in most Linux systems, that's the default Shell.
它也与其他Shell(如zsh)兼容,非常实用.
And it's also kind of backward compatible through other Shells like zsh, it's pretty nice.
然后,我们将介绍一些非常方便的Shell工具,
And then we're gonna cover some other Shell tools that are really convenient,
可以让你免做一些重复的任务,
so you avoid doing like really repetitive tasks,
例如查找某些代码或某些藏得很深的文件.
like looking for some piece of code or for some elusive file.
Shell中一些内置命令已经非常有用,
And there are already kind of really nice built-in commands
可以帮助你完成这些任务.
that will kind of really help you to do those things.
昨天,我们已经介绍了Shell的一些特性,
So yesterday we already kind of introduced you to the Shell and kind of like it's quirks,
比如如何执行命令并对他们重定向等等.
and some like how you start executing commands,redirecting them.
今天,我们将更详细地介绍Shell的变量语法、流程控制和函数等内容.
Today, we're gonna kind of cover more about like the syntax of more \N like the variables, the control flow,functions of the Shell.
例如,一旦你进入Shell,你可能想要定义一个变量,
So for example, once you kind of drop into a Shell, say you want to kind of define a variable,
这是学习编程语言的第一步.
which is kind of one of the first things you learn to do in a programming language.
在这里,你可以执行类似foo=bar的操作.
Here you could do something like "foo=bar".
现在,我们可以通过"$foo"来访问"foo"的值.
And now we can access the value of "foo" by doing "$foo".
结果为"bar",完美.
And that's "bar", perfect.
需要注意的一个问题是,
One quirk that you need to be aware of is that
在使用bash的时候,空格非常关键.
spaces are really critical when you're dealing with bash.
主要是因为空格是用于分隔参数的字符.
Mainly because spaces are reserved, and that will be for separating arguments.
因此,例如,foo = bar将不起作用,
So, for example, something like "foo = bar" won't work,
Shell会告诉你为什么不起作用.
and the Shell is gonna tell you why it's not working.
这是因为"foo"命令并没有执行,例如这里提示说"foo"不存在.
It's because the "foo" command is not working, like "foo" is non-existent.
事实上,我们并没有把"foo"分配到"bar"
And here what is actually happening, we're not assigning "foo" to "bar",
换句话说,我们调用"foo"程序时,第一个参数是"=",第二个参数是"bar".
what is happening is we're calling the "foo" program with the first argument "=" and the second argument "bar".
通常情况下,当你遇到一些问题时,例如一些带有空格的文件时,
And in general, whenever you are having some issues, like some files with spaces
需要小心处理.
you will need to be careful about that.
注意要用引号把含空格的字符串引起来.
You need to be careful about quoting strings.
接下来,我们将讨论在bash中如何使用字符串.
So, going into that, how you do strings in bash.
有两种方法可以定义字符串：
There are two ways that you can define a string:
你可以使用双引号("")定义字符串,
You can define strings using double quotes
也可以使用单引号('')定义字符串.
and you can define strings using single,
错辣,
Sorry,
是用单引号('')
using single quotes.
对于纯文本字符串,它们是等效的,
However, for literal strings they are equivalent,
但对于有些情况则不然.
but for the rest they are not equivalent.
例如,如果我们执行echo "Value is $foo",
So, for example, if we do `echo "Value is $foo"`,
则会将"$foo"展开为字符串,
The "$foo" has been kind of expanded like a string
并将其替换为Shell中"foo"的值.
substituted to the value of the "foo" variable in the Shell.
而如果我们使用单引号,则就仅仅是"$foo",
Whereas if we do this with single quotes, we are just getting the "$foo" as it is
即单引号不会进行替换.
and like single quotes won't be replacing.
所以写bash脚本真的很简单,
And again,it's really easy to write a script,
这类似于你可能更熟悉的Python,
assume that this is kind of like Python, that you might be more familiar with,
只是你暂时还没有意识到这一点.
and not realize all that.
这就是你给变量赋值的方式.
And this is the way you will assign variables.
然后,bash还可以进行流程控制,例如for循环、while循环,
Then bash also has control flow techniques that we'll see later,like for loops, while loops,
更主要的是你可以定义函数.
and one main thing is you can define functions.
我们可以调用我在这里定义的一个函数
And we can access like a function I have defined here.
我们可以访问此处定义的"mcd"函数.
And here we have the "mcd" function, that has been defined,
目前为止,我们只是演示了
and the thing is, so far, we have just kind of seen
通过将多个命令使用管道传输来执行这些命令,
how to execute several commands by piping into them,
昨天已经简要介绍了这个.
kind of saw that briefly yesterday.
但是在很多情况下,你会想先执行一件事,然后再做另一件事.
But a lot of times you want to do first one thing and then another thing.
这就像我们这里的这个按序执行的例子一样.
And that's kind of like the sequential execution that we get here.
例如,在这里,我们调用了"mcd"函数.
Here, for example, we're calling the "mcd" function.
我们首先调用"mkdir"命令来创建这个目录.
And we, first,are calling the "mkdir" command, which is like creating this directory.
在这里,"$1"是一种特殊变量.
Here, "$1" is like a special variable.
这是bash的一种特性,类似于其他脚本语言里的"argv",
This is the way that bash works,whereas in other scripting languages there will be like "argv",
"argv"第一项将包含该参数.
the first item of the array "argv" will contain the argument.
在bash中,它被表示为"$1".
In bash it's "$1".
通常,在bash中,有许多"$"开头的东西,
And in general, a lot of things in bash will be "$..."
这表明它们是保留关键字,稍后我们会看到更多例子.
and will be reserved, we will be seeing more examples later.
一旦我们创建了文件夹,我们就进入该文件夹,
And once we have created the folder, we cd into that folder,
这是相当常见的情况.
which is kind of a fairly common pattern that you will see.
我们可以在Shell中直接输入这个命令,
We will actually type this directly into our Shell,
它会定义该函数并起作用.
and it will work  and it will define this function.
但是,有时将这些内容写入文件会更好.
But sometimes it's nicer to kind of write things in a file.
我们可以使用source mcd.sh
What we can do is we can source this.
这会在我们的Shell中加载并执行这个脚本.
And that will execute this script in our Shell and load it.
现在看起来好像什么都没有发生,
So now it looks like nothing happened,
但是我们的Shell中已经定义了"mcd"函数.
but now the "mcd" function has been defined in our Shell.
我们现在可以执行"mcd test"命令来试试,
So we can now for example do like "mcd test",
然后我们从"tools"目录移动到"test"目录.
and now we move from the "tools" directory to the "test" directory.
我们先创建了文件夹,然后进入了它.
We both created the folder and we moved into it.
还有什么?
What else. So a result is...
我们可以使用"$1"来访问第一个参数.
We can access the first argument with "$1".
还有很多保留关键字,
There's a lot more kind of  reserved commands for example,
例如"$0"表示脚本的名称,
"$0" will be the name of the script,
"$2"到"$9"将是bash脚本接收的第二到第九个参数.
"$2" through "$9" will be the second through the ninth arguments that the bash script takes.
其中一些保留关键字可以直接在Shell中使用,
Some of these reserved keywords can be directly used in the Shell,
例如"$?"可以获取上一个命令的错误代码,
so for example "$?" will get you the error code from the previous command,
这个我等会会简要解释一下.
and which I'll also explain briefly.
例如"$_"可以获取上一个命令的最后一个参数.
But for example, "$_ " will get you the last argument of the previous command.
因此,我们也可以这样做,例如使用mkdir test,
So another way we could have done this is we could have said like "mkdir test"
而不需要重复输入"test",
and instead of rewriting test,
我们可以使用"$_"作为上一个命令的一部分来访问上一个参数,
we can access that last argument as part of the (previous command),
这样它将被替换为"test",然后我们进入"test".
using "$_" ,like that will be replaced with "test" and now we go into "test".
还有很多这样的命令,你应该熟悉它们.
There are a lot of them, you should familiarize with them.
我经常使用的另一个命令叫做"!!",
Another one I often use is kind of is called "bang bang" ("!!"),
当你尝试创建某些东西时但没有足够权限的时候,它就很有用.
you will run into this whenever you, for example, \N are trying to create something and you don't have enough permissions.
然后,你可以执行sudo !!命令,
Then, you can do "sudo !!"
然后"!!"会被替换为上一次的命令,现在你可以再执行一次.
and then that will replace the command in there and now you can just try doing that.
现在它会提示你输入密码,因为你拥有sudo权限.
And now it will prompt you for a password,because you have sudo permissions.
刚刚,我提到了执行命令出现error.
Before, I mentioned the kind of the error command.
昨天我们提到,进程可以通过不同的方式
Yesterday we saw that, in general, there are like different ways
与其他进程或命令进行通信.
a process can communicate with other processes or commands.
我们提过标准输入(流),
We mentioned the standard input,
这个不像从标准输入流中读取或是输出到标准输出流
which also was less than like getting stuff through the standard input, \N putting stuff into the standard output.
这里有很多有意思的东西,比如说标准错误流,
There are a couple more interesting things, there's also like a standard error,
它用于在程序编写时输出错误信息,
a stream where you write errors that happen with your program
以避免污染标准输出.
and you don't want to pollute the standard output.
还有错误代码这种东西,这是许多编程语言中都有的,
There's also the error code, which is like a general thing in a lot of programming languages,
它可以报告程序的整体运行情况.
some way of reporting how the entire run of something went.
因此,如果我们执行像echo "hello"这样的命令,
So if we do  something like 'echo "hello"'
并且检查其错误代码,它将为0.
and we like query for the value, it's zero.
这是因为一切都很顺利,没有出现任何问题.
And it's "zero" because everything went okay and there weren't any issues.
"0"的退出代码与C语言中的退出代码相同,
And a "0" exit code is the same as you will get in a language like c,
例如"0"表示一切顺利,没有错误.
like "0" means everything went fine, there were no errors.
但是,有时事情并不按照我们预期的方式进行.
However, sometimes things won't work.
例如,如果我们执行grep foobar mcd.sh,
Sometimes, like if we try to "grep" for "foobar" in our "mcd.sh",
然后检查其错误代码,它将为1.
and now we check for that value, it's "1".
这是因为我们试图在"mcd.sh"中搜索"foobar"字符串,
And that's because we tried to search for the "foobar" string in the "mcd.sh"
但是该字符串不存在.
and it wasn't there.
因此,"grep"不会输出任何内容,
So "grep" doesn't print anything,
但是会返回一个1的错误代码告诉我们发生了错误.
but let us know that things didn't work by giving us a "1" error code.
还有一些有趣的命令,比如"true",它的错误代码始终为"0",
There are some interesting commands like "true", for example, will always have a "0" error code,
而"false"的错误代码始终为1.
and "false" will always have a "1" error code.
通过使用这些逻辑运算符,我们可以执行某些条件语句.
Then there are like these logical operators that you can use to do some sort of conditionals for example
例如,你还可以用"if-else",这个我们稍后再说
one way...you also have "if"s and "else"s, that we will see later,
你可以输入一些命令,例如false || echo "Oops fail"
But you can do something like "false", and 'echo "Oops fail" '.
这里,我们使用"||"(或)运算符连接两个命令
So here we have two commands connected by this "||" operator.
然后在这里,bash会执行第一个命令
What bash is gonna do here, it's gonna execute the first one
如果第一个命令失败,则bash将执行第二个命令.
and if the first one didn't work, then it's gonna execute the second one.
所以在这里我们得到了这个结果,因为它是一个逻辑或.
So here we get it,because it's gonna try to do a logical OR.
如果第一个命令失败,则bash将执行第二个命令.
If the first one didn't have a "0" error code, it's gonna try to do the second one.
同样的,如果我们不用false,我们用true
Similarly, if we instead of use "false", we use something like "true",
因为执行true不会报错,
since "true" will have a "0" error code,
第二个命令就会跳过(短路[*])并且不会打印出来
then the second one will be short-circuited and it won't be printed.
*[这里是逻辑表达式的短路~]
同样,使用与运算符连接两个命令时,
Similarly, we have an AND operator
只有在第一个命令没有错误的情况下才会执行第二个命令.
which will only execute the second part if the first one ran without errors.
和之前(逻辑或)一样,
And the same thing will happen.
如果第一个命令失败,则bash将不会执行第二个命令.
If the first one fails, then the second part of this thing won't be executed.
此外,无论执行什么命令,
Kind of not exactly related to that, but another thing that you will see is
都可以使用";"将它们连接在同一行中,
that no matter what you execute, then you can concatenate commands
并将它们打印出来.
using a semicolon in the same line,and that will always print.
除此之外,例如我们现在还不知道
Beyond that, what we haven't seen, for example,
如何将一个命令的输出存储到一个变量中.
is how you go about kind of getting the output of a command into a variable.
我们可以通过这样做来实现.
And the way we can do that is doing something like this.
在这里,我们获取了pwd命令的输出,
What we're doing here is we're getting the output of the "pwd" command,
该命令只是打印我们现在所在的当前工作目录,
which is just printing the present working directory where we are right now.
然后将其存储到"foo"变量中.
And then we're storing that into the "foo" variable.
然后我们查看一下"foo",我们就能看到之前存储的路径.
So we do that and then we ask for "foo", we view our string.
更一般地说,
And more generally,
我们可以将它放入字符串中来执行"命令替换"[*].
we can do this thing called command substitution by putting it into any string.
*[命令替换是一种在Unix、Linux和类Unix操作系统中常见的技术，用于在一个命令的输出中嵌套另一个命令。]
由于我们使用的是双引号("")而不是单引号(''),
And since we're using double quotes instead of single quotes
这个东西将被扩展,并告诉我们现在所在的位置.
that thing will be expanded and it will tell us that we are in this working folder.
另一个有趣的事情是,
Another interesting thing is,
现在,这个东西扩展为一个字符串,而不是...
right now, what this is expanding to is a string instead of kind of like,
它只是扩展为一个字符串.
it's just expanding as a string.
另一个小众的工具称为进程替换,它和命令替换有点类似.
Another nifty and lesser known tool is called process substitution which is kind of similar.
怎么做呢.
What it will do...
这里,例如,"<"加上命令,再套上括号,
It will, here for example, the "<", some command and another parenthesis,
它的作用是,它会内部执行,然后将输出放到
what that will do is, that will execute, that will get the output to
一个类似临时文件的东西中,并将文件标识符提供给最左边命令.
kind of like a temporary file and it will give the file handle to the command.
所以在这里,
So here what we're doing is we're getting...
我们正在查看这个目录,
we're LS'ing the directory, putting it into a temporary file,
将其放入一个临时文件中,对父文件夹做同样的事情,
doing the same thing for the parent folder
然后将两个文件连接起来.
and then we're concatenating both files.
这可能非常方便,
And this will, might be really handy,
因为一些命令不是从标准输入流中获取输入的,
because some commands instead of expecting the input coming from the stdin,
而是从某些文件中获取的.
they are expecting things to come from \N some file that is giving some of the arguments.
所以我们得到了两个命令连接在一起的输出.
So we get kind of both things concatenated.
我认为到目前为止已经讲了不少东西,
I think so far there's been a lot of information,
让我们看一个简单的脚本示例,
let's see kind of a simple,
在其中我们可以看到一些这些东西的应用.
an example script where we see a few of these things.
例如在这里我们有一个字符串和一个"$(date)".
So for example here we have a string and we have kind of this "$(date)".
"$(date)"是一个程序.
So "$(date)" is a program.
UNIX中有很多程序,你将慢慢地熟悉.
Again there's a lot of programs in UNIX you will kind of slowly familiarize with a lot of them.
date只是打印当前日期,你可以指定不同的格式.
"date" just prints what the current date is and you can specify different formats.
接下来,我们有这些"$0".
Then, we have these "$0" here.
"$0"是我们正在运行的脚本的文件名.
"$0" is the name of the script that we're running.
然后我们有"$#",这是我们给该命令的参数数量,
Then we have "$#", that's the number of arguments that we are giving to the command,
然后"$$"是正在运行的该命令的进程ID[*].
and then "$$" is the process ID of this command that is running.
*[也简称PID]
再次提醒,这里有很多"$"符号,它们不直观,
Again, there's a lot of kind of these dollar things, they're not intuitive
因为它们没有一种助记的记忆方式,比如"$#".
because they don't have like a mnemonic way of remembering, maybe, "$#".
但是用得多了就会逐渐熟悉它们.
But it can be... you will just be seeing them and getting familiar with them.
这里我们有"$@",它将展开为所有的参数.
Here we have this "$@", and that will expand to all the arguments.
因此,不必假定可能有三个参数而编写"$1","$2","$3",
So, instead of having to assume that, maybe say,\N  we have three arguments and writing "$1", "$2", "$3",
如果我们不知道有多少参数,我们可以将所有这些参数放在那里.
if we don't know how many arguments we can put all those arguments there.
然后将其传递给for循环.
And that has been given to a for loop.
for循环将依次创建"file"变量,
And the for loop will, in time, get like the file variable
并将每个参数逐一赋值给"file".
and it will be giving each one of the arguments. \N So what we're doing is, for every one of the arguments we're giving.
接下来,在下一行中,我们运行"grep"命令,
Then, in the next line we're running the "grep" command
它只是在某个文件中搜索子字符串,
which is just search for a substring in some file
这里我们在文件中搜索字符串"foobar".
and we're searching for the string "foobar" in the file.
我们将"file"变量展开.
Here, we kind of have put the variable that the file took to expand.
昨天,如果我们关心程序的输出,
And yesterday we saw that like if we care about the output of a program,
我们可以将其重定向到某个地方,以保存它或连接到其他文件.
we can redirect it to somewhere to save it or like to connect it to some other file.
但是有时候我们想要相反的效果.
But sometimes you want the opposite.
有时,例如在这里,
Sometimes, here for example, we care...
我们需要关注错误代码.
we're gonna care about the error code.
对于这个脚本,我们想知道"grep"命令是否成功运行.
About this script, we're gonna care whether the "grep" ran successfully or it didn't.
我们完全可以忽略输出,
So we can actually discard entirely what the output
就像"grep"命令的标准输出流和标准错误流一样.
like both the standard output and the standard error of the "grep" command.
我们要做的是将输出重定向到"/dev/null"[*],
And what we're doing is we're redirecting the output to "/dev/null"
*["/dev/null"被称为黑洞文件,顾名思义,就像黑洞一样~]
这是UNIX系统中的一种特殊设备,
which is kind of like a special device in UNIX systems where you can like write and it will be discarded.
你可以像写入文件一样写入数据,但它将被丢弃.
Like you can write no matter how much you want there, and it will be discarded.
这里有一个">"符号,我们昨天已经知道它用于重定向.
And here's the ">" symbol that we saw yesterday for redirecting output.
这里有一个"2>",正如一些人可能已经猜到的那样,
Here you have a "2>" and, as some of you might have guessed by now,
这是用于重定向标准错误流的,
this is for redirecting the standard error,
因为这两个流是分开的,
because those two streams are separate,
你需要告诉bash如何处理它们.
and you kind of have to tell bash what to do with each one of them.
所以在这里,我们检查文件是否包含"foobar",
So here, we run, we check if the file has "foobar",
如果文件包含"foobar",它将返回0.
and if the file has "foobar" then it's going to have a "0" code.
如果没有"foobar",它将返回非0的错误代码.
If it doesn't have "foobar", it's gonna have a nonzero error code.
因此,这正是我们检查的内容.
So that's exactly what we check in this
在这个if命令的一部分中,我们说"给我错误代码".
"if" part of the command we say "get me the error code".
这里用了"$?"
Again, this "$?".
然后我们有一个比较运算符:
And then we have a comparison operator:
"-ne",表示"not equal"(不相等).
which is "-ne", for "not equal".
有些其他编程语言有"=="、"!="这些比较符.
And like some other programming languages will have "==", "!=",
在bash中还有一系列的比较运算符,
these symbols in bash there's kind of like a reserved set of comparisons
这主要是因为你可能需要测试很多东西
and it's mainly because there's a lot of things you might want to test for
当你在shell中进行测试时,
when you're in the Shell.
例如,在这里,我们只是检查两个整数值是否相同.
Here for example we're just checking for the two values, two integer values, being the same.
或者例如在这里,"-f"检查文件是否存在,
Or for example here, the "-f" check will let us know if a file exists,
这是你经常会遇到的一些事情.
which is something that you will run into very,very commonly.
我回到这个例子.
I'm going back to the example.
当文件没有"foobar"时会发生什么,
Then, what happens when we,if the file did not have "foobar",
就会返回非零错误代码,
like there was a nonzero error code,
接着会打印:"这个文件中没有'foobar',我们将添加一个".
then we print: this file doesn't have any "foobar",we're going to add one.
我们所做的是echo "# foobar",希望这是对文件的注释,
And what we do is we echo this "# foobar", hoping this is a comment to the file
然后我们使用运算符">>"在文件末尾追加.
and then we're using the operator ">>" to append at the end of the file.
因为文件名已经被传递给脚本,
Here since the file has been fed through the script,
我们之前不知道文件名,所以我们用了"file"变量,现在要将它展开.
and we don't know it beforehand, we have to substitute the variable of the filename.
我们可以运行这个脚本.
We can actually run this.
我们已经在这个脚本中具有正确的权限,我们可以举出一些例子.
We already have correct permissions in this script and we can give a few examples.
在此文件夹中,我们有一些文件,"mcd.sh"是我们在开头看到的"mcd"函数,
We have a few files in this folder, "mcd.sh" is the one we saw at the beginning for the "mcd" function,
还有一些其他的脚本,我们甚至可以将这个脚本也放到输入中,
some other "script" function and we can even feed the own script to itself to check
以检查它是否包含"foobar".
if it has "foobar" in it.
然后我们运行它,首先可以看到许多已经被扩展了的变量.
And we run it and first we can see that there's different variables that we saw, \N that have been successfully expanded.
我们有date命令,已经被替换为当前时间,
We have date that has been replaced to the current time,
然后我们传递三个参数给这个程序,
then we're running this program, with three arguments,
这是随机生成的PID[*],
this randomized PID,
*[PID代表进程标识符(Process Identifier)。\N 每个运行中的进程都有一个唯一的PID，用于在操作系统中标识该进程。]
然后它告诉我们"mcd.sh"没有任何"foobar",所以我们正在添加一个新的,
and it's telling us "mcd" doesn't have any "foobar", so we are adding a new one,
这个脚本文件也没有"foobar".
and this script file doesn't have one.
现在让我们来看看"mcd.sh",它现在有了"foobar"注释.
So now for example let's look at "mcd" and it has the comment that we were looking for.
当你执行脚本时,还有一件事需要知道,
One other thing to know when you're kind of executing scripts
就是这里有三个完全不同的参数,
is that here we have like three completely different arguments
但有时候你不需要一个个输入文件名.
but very commonly you will be given arguments \N that can be more succinctly given in some way.
例如,在这里,如果我们想引用所有的".sh"脚本,
So for example here if we wanted to refer to all the ".sh" scripts
我们可以做一些像ls *.sh的事情,
we could just do something like "ls *.sh"
这是大多数shell都有的一种文件名扩展方式.
and this is a way of kind of filename expansion that most Shells have
称为"globbing"(通配符)的
that's called "globbing".
在这里,正如你所想,
Here, as you might expect, this is gonna say anything
这将显示任何以".sh"结尾的文件.
that has any kind of sort of characters and ends up with ".sh".
显然,我们确实得到了"example.sh"和"mcd.sh".
Unsurprisingly, we get "example.sh" and "mcd.sh".
我们还有这些"project1"和"project2",
We also have these "project1" and "project2",
如果有一个...
and if there were like a...
我们可以创建一个"project42",
we can do a "project42", for example
例如,现在如果我们只想匹配"project"后面加一个字符,
And now if we just want to refer to the projects that have a single character,
而不是两个字符.
but not two characters afterwards,
我们可以使用"?".
like any other characters, we can use the question mark.
所以"?"将扩展为一个任意字符.
So "?" will expand to only a single one.
我们得到,第一个是"project1"然后是"project2"
And we get, lsing, first "project1" and then "project2".
通常情况下,通配符可以非常强大.你也可以结合使用.
Another kind of the...globbing can be very powerful. You can also combine it.
还有一个比较常见的模式是用花括号("\").
A common pattern is to use what is called curly braces.
假设我们有一个图像,在这个文件夹中,
So let's say we have an image, that we have in this folder
我们想将这个图像从PNG转换为JPG,
and we want to convert this image from PNG to JPG
或者我们可以复制它,
or we could maybe copy it,
这是一个非常常见的情况,有两个或更多相似的参数,
or it's a really common pattern, to have two or more arguments
你想将它们作为参数传递给某个命令.
that are fairly similar and you want to do something with them \N as arguments to some command.
你可以这样做,你也可以用更加简介的方式
You could do it this way, or more succinctly,
你只要输入"image.\"就可以了
you can just do "image."
在这里,我得到了一些彩色的反馈.
And here, I'm getting some color feedback.
反正它会扩展为上面那行.
but what this will do, is expand into the line above.
实际上,我可以让zsh替我做到这一点.
Actually, I can ask zsh to do that for me and that what's happening here.
这真的很nice.
This is really powerful.
例如,你可以做一些像...
So for example you can do something like...
我们可以"touch"一串"foo",所有这些都会被扩展.
we could do "touch" on a bunch of "foo"s, and all of this will be expanded.
你还可以多层操作,他们将做笛卡尔积...
You can also do it at several levels and you will do the Cartesian...
如果我们有一些这样的组,
We have something like this, we have one group here,
"\",然后这里有"\",
"\" and then here there's "\",
这将以这两个组的笛卡尔积进行扩展,
and this is going to do the Cartesian product of these two expansions
并将扩展为所有这些东西,我们可以快速地创建文件.
and it will expand into all these things,that we can quickly "touch".
你还可以将"*"与"\"结合使用.
You can also combine the asterisk glob with the curly braces glob.
你甚至可以使用类似于区间的东西.
You can even use kind of ranges.
比如,我们可以做"mkdir",
Like, we can do "mkdir"
并创建"foo"和"bar"目录,
and we create the "foo" and the "bar" directories,
然后我们可以做类似这样的事情.
and then we can do something along these lines.
这将会扩展到"foo/a","foo/b"...所有这些组合,一直到"j",
This is going to expand to "foo/a", "foo/b" like all these combinations, through "j",
然后对于"bar"同样如此.
and then the same for "bar".
我还没有真正测试过它...
I haven't really tested it...
但是是的,我们得到了所有这些我们可以"touch"的组合.
but yeah, we're getting all these combinations that we can "touch".
现在,我们如果在这两个目录创建俩不同的文件,
And now, if we touch something that is different between these two (directories),
我们可以再演示一下之前的进程替换.
we can again showcase the process substitution that we saw earlier.
比如我们想检查这两个文件夹之间有哪些文件不同.
So  we want to check what files are different between these two folders.
对于我们来说很明显,我们刚刚看到了,是"x"和"y",
For us it's obvious, we just saw it, it's "x" and "y",
但是我们可以要求shell进行"diff",
but we can ask the Shell to do this "diff" for us
并且让它在两个"ls"的输出之间作比较.
between the output of one "ls" and the other "ls".
毫不奇怪,我们得到的结果是:
Unsurprisingly we're getting:
"x"只存在于第一个文件夹中,
"x" is only in the first folder
而"y"只存在于第二个文件夹中.
and "y" is only in the second folder.
我们现在只看到了bash脚本.
What is more is, right now, we have only seen bash scripts.
如果你喜欢其他脚本,
If you like other scripts,
对于某些任务,bash可能不是最好的,可能会很棘手.
like for some tasks bash is probably not the best,it can be tricky.
你实际上可以用许多不同语言来实现与shell交互的脚本.
You can actually write scripts that interact with the Shell implemented in a lot of different languages.
所以,例如,让我们看一下这里.
So for example, let's see here...
一个Python脚本,在开头有一个魔法行,我现在不解释.
Python script that has a magic line at the beginning that I'm not explaining for now.
然后我们有"import sys",
Then we have "import sys",it's kind of like the...
Python默认情况下不会与shell交互,
Python is not, by default, trying to interact with the Shell,
所以你需要导入一些库.
so you will have to import some library.
然后我们正在做一件非常简单的事,就是遍历"sys.argv[1:]".
And then we're doing a really silly thing of just iterating over "sys.argv[1:]".
"sys.argv"有点类似于在bash中我们得到的"$0","$1"等,
"sys.argv" is kind of similar to what in bash we're getting as "$0", "$1",etc
就像参数向量一样,我们将其按相反的顺序打印出来.
Like the vector of the arguments, we're printing it in the reversed order.
开头的魔法行叫做shebang,
And the magic line at the beginning is called a shebang
是让shell知道如何运行这个脚本.
and is the way that the Shell will know how to run this program.
你总是可以做一些像"python script.py"这样的事情,然后"a b c",
Like you can always do something like "python script.py", and then like "a b c"
这样可以运行.
and that will work, always, like that.
但是,如果我们想让它在shell中直接执行呢?
But what if we want to make this to be executable from the Shell?
shell知道它必须使用python作为解释器
The way the Shell knows that it has to use python as the interpreter
这样才能通过shebang的方式来运行此文件.
to run this file is using that first line.
shebang展示的就是运行这个脚本的程序所在路径.
And that first line is giving it the path to where that thing lives.
但是,你可能不知道.
However, you might not know,like,
不同的机器可能会将python放在不同的位置,
different machines will have probably different places where they put python
你可能无法提前知道python或者其他解释器安装在哪里.
and you might not want to assume where python is installed, or any other interpreter.
所以你可以使用"env".
So one thing that you can do is use the "env" command.
你也可以在shebang中给出参数,
You can also give arguments in the shebang,
所以我们在这里指定运行"env"命令,
so what we're doing here is specifying run the "env" command,
对于几乎所有系统来说,有一些例外,
that is for pretty much every system, there are some exceptions,
但是对于几乎所有系统来说,
but like for pretty much every system
它都在"usr/bin"中,那里有很多二进制文件,
it's is in "usr/bin", where a lot of binaries live,
然后我们用参数"python"调用它
and then we're calling it with the argument "python".
然后它将利用我们在第一节课上学到的路径环境变量.
And then that will make use of the path environment variable that we saw in the first lecture.
它将在该路径中搜索Python二进制文件,
It's gonna search in that path for the Python binary
然后使用它来解释该文件.
and then it's gonna use that to interpret this file.
这将使得它的可移植性变强了,
And that will make this more portable
因此这个脚本可以在我的电脑、你的电脑和其他电脑上运行.
so it can be run in my machine, and your machine and some other machine.
另一件事是,bash并不现代化,
Another thing is that the bash is not really like modern,
它是很久以前开发的.
it was developed a while ago.
有时调试起来可能会很棘手.
And sometimes it can be tricky to debug.
默认情况下,有些故障可能不太直观,
By default, and the ways it will fail sometimes are intuitive
例如我们之前看到的"foo"命令不存在.
like the way we saw before of like "foo" command not existing, sometimes it's not.
因此,在课堂笔记中我们提供了一个叫做"shellcheck"的工具,
So there's like a really nifty tool that we have linked in the lecture notes, which is called "shellcheck",
它可以为你提供警告、语法错误
that will kind of give you both warnings and syntactic errors
和其他可能不正确引用
and other things that you might not have quoted properly,
或文件中错放空格的问题.
or you might have misplaced spaces in your files.
例如,对于非常简单的"mcd.sh"文件,我们会得到一些错误提示,
So for example for extremely simple "mcd.sh" file we gonna hava a couple of errors saying hey,
令人惊讶的是,我们缺少了shebang,
surprisingly,we're missing a shebang,
如果在不同的系统上运行,可能无法正确解释它.
like this might not interpret it correctly if you're running it at a different system.
此外,这个"cd"命令可能不会正确扩展,
Also, this "cd" is taking a command and it might not expand properly
因此,与其使用"cd",不如使用其他方法
so instead of using "cd" you might want to use something
像是使用类似于"cd ... || exit"这样的东西.
like "cd ... || exit".
我们回到之前解释的内容,
We go back to what we explained earlier,
这样做的效果就是,如果"cd"没有正确执行,
what this will do is like if the "cd" doesn't end correctly,
你不能"cd"进入该文件夹,因为要么你没有权限,要么它不存在...
you cannot "cd" into the folder because either you don't have permissions, it doesn't exist...
这将返回一个非0的错误代码,
That will give a nonzero error command,
脚本将执行"exit",这将停止脚本的运行,
so you will execute "exit" and that will stop the script
而不是继续对实际并不存在的地方执行命令.
instead of continue executing as if you were in a place that you are actually not in.
实际上,我还没有测试过,
And actually I haven't tested,
但我认为我们可以检查"example.sh",
but I think we can check for the "example.sh"
在这里我们得到的是我们应该以不同的方式检查退出代码,
and here we're getting that we should be checking the exit code in a different way,
因为这种方法可能不是最好的方法.
because it's probably not the best way, doing it this way.
我还想强调一点,在编写bash脚本或函数时,
One last remark I want to make is that when you're writing bash scripts or functions for that matter,
直接运行脚本/函数和载入shell的脚本/函数是有区别的
there's kind of a difference between writing bash scripts in isolation \N like a thing that you're gonna run, and a thing that you're gonna load into your Shell.
我们将在命令行环境讲座中看到一些内容,
We will see some of this in the command line environment lecture,
那里我们将会处理bashrc和sshrc.
where we will kind of be tooling with the bashrc and the sshrc.
但总的来说,如果你对例如你所在的所在路径进行更改,
But in general, if you make changes to for example where you are,
例如如果你"cd"到一个bash脚本并且只执行该bash脚本,
like if you "cd" into a bash script and you just execute that bash script,
这个脚本就不会"cd"到shell当前所在路径
it won't "cd" into the Shell are right now.
但是,如果你直接将代码加载到你的shell中,例如你加载......
But if you have loaded the code directly into your Shell, for example we load the...
你找到函数并执行该函数,
You source the function and then you execute the function
那么它就可以直接在你当前路径执行.
then you will get those side effects.
同样的道理也适用于在shell中定义的变量.
And the same goes for defining variables into the Shell.
现在我将讨论一些我认为在处理shell时非常好用的工具.
Now I gonna kind of talk about some tools that I think are nifty when working with the Shell.
这也是昨天简单介绍过的.
The first was also briefly introduced yesterday.
你如何知道使用哪些选项或确切的命令.
How do you know what flags, or like what exact commands can go
比如我该如何知道"ls -l"会以列表格式列出文件,
like how I am supposed to know that "ls -l" will list the files in a list format,
或者如果我执行"mv -i",它会提示我输入内容.
or that if I do "mv - i", it's gonna like prom me for stuff.
为此,你可以使用"man"命令.
For that what you have is the "man" command.
"man"命令会提供很多帮助信息...
And the "man" command will kind of have \N like a lot of information of how will you go about...
例如在这里它会解释"-i"选项
so for example here it will explain for the "-i" flag,
有哪些可选项.
there are all these options you can do.
这其实非常有用,
That's actually pretty useful and it will work
不仅适用于你操作系统中打包好的简单命令,
not only for really simple commands that come packaged with your OS
而且还适用于你从互联网上安装的一些工具.
but will also work with some tools that you install from the internet for example
例如,如果安装工具的同时安装了"man"包,
if the person that did the installation made it so that the "man" package were also installed.
比如我们稍后要介绍的一个名为"ripgrep"的工具,
So for example a tool that we're gonna cover in a bit
它的命令叫做"rg",
which is called "ripgrep" and is called with "rg",
这并没有与我的系统一起提供,
and this didn't come with my system
但它一同安装了自己的"man"页面,我可以访问它.
but it has installed its own man page and I have it here and I can access it.
对于某些命令,"man"页面是有用的,
For some commands the man page is useful
但有时它又不太方便,
but sometimes it can be tricky to decipher
因为它更像是一份文档或是描述工具
because it's more kind of a documentation
关于所能做的所有事情的说明.
and a description of all the things the tool can do.
有时它会有示例,但有时不会,
Sometimes it will have examples but sometimes not,
有时工具可以做很多事情,
and sometimes the tool can do a lot of things.
比如我经常使用的一些好工具是"convert"或"ffmpeg",
So a couple of good tools that I use commonly are "convert" or "ffmpeg",
它们分别处理图像和视频,"man"页内容巨多.
which deal with images and video respectively and the "man" pages are like enormous.
你还可以安装一个很好的,叫做"tldr"的工具,
So there's one neat tool called "tldr" that you can install
然后你就可以得到一些很好的例子,
and you will have like some nice kind of explanatory examples of
来解释如何使用这个命令.
how you want to use this command.
当然你也可以随时在谷歌上搜索,
And you can always Google for this,
但我发现我总是要先进入浏览器,
but I find myself saving going into the browser,
查找一些例子,然后再回来(这很慢~),而"tldr"是社区贡献的,
looking about some examples and coming back, whereas "tldr" are community contributed
使用"tldr"效率就非常高.
and they're fairly useful.
然后,"ffmpeg"的页面有很多有用的例子,
Then, the one for "ffmpeg" has a lot of useful examples
这些例子的格式也很美观
that are more nicely formatted
如果你特意用大号字体的话.
if you don't have a huge font size for recording.
甚至于像"tar"这样的简单命令,有很多选项需要组合使用.
Or even simple commands like "tar", that have a lot of options that you are combining.
例如,在这里,你可以组合2、3个不同的flag,
So for example, here you can be combining 2, 3... different flags
当你想组合不同的flag时,可能不是很直观
and it can not be obvious, when you want to combine different ones.
"tldr"就可以帮你更快了解这些工具.
That's how you would go about finding more about these tools.
现在让我们学学如何查找文件.
On the topic of finding, let's try learning how to find files.
你可以随时使用ls,比如ls project1,并不断ls到底.
You can always go "ls", and like you can go like "ls project1", and keep LS'ing all the way through.
但是,也许如果我们已经知道我们要查找所有名为"src"的文件夹,
But maybe, if we already know that we want to look for all the folders called "src",
那么可能有更好的命令来完成这个任务.
then there's probably a better command for doing that.
这就是"find".
And that's "find".
"find"是几乎每个UNIX系统都带有的工具.
"find" is the tool that, pretty much comes with every UNIX system.
我们要将把"find"用在...
And "find", we're gonna give it...
我们将在当前文件夹中调用"find" ,
here we're saying we want to call "find" in the current folder,
别忘了"."表示当前文件夹,
remember that "." stands for the current folder,
我们要让它的名称是"src",类型为文件夹.
and we want the name to be "src" and we want the type to be a directory.
通过输入这个命令,它将递归地浏览当前文件夹,
And by typing that it's gonna recursively go through the current directory
并查找所有符合此标准的文件或文件夹.
and look for all these files, or folders in this case, that match this pattern.
"find"有很多有用的标志.
"find" has a lot of useful flags.
例如,你甚至可以查询特定模式的文件路径.
So for example, you can even test for the path to be in a way.
以便说我们希望有一些文件夹,
Here we're saying we want some number of folders,
我们并不在意有多少文件夹,
we don't really care how many folders,
然后我们想要的是所有的Python脚本,
and then we care about all the Python scripts,
所有的扩展名为".py"的东西,
all the things with the extension ".py",
这些都需要在一个名为"test"的文件夹中.
that are within a test folder.
而且,我们也检查一下,只是以防万一,
And we're also checking, just in cases really
但我们只是检查一下它也是"f"(文件)类型
but we're checking just that it's also are...
"-type f"代表查找类型是文件
"-type f", which stands for file.
我们正在获取所有符合条件的文件.
We're getting all these files.
你还可以使用路径或类型之外的标志.
You can also use different flags for things that are not the path or the name.
比如你可以检查已修改过的文件
You could check things that have been modified
"-mtime"用于修改时间,
"-mtime" is for the modification time,
在过去一天内修改过的文件,这几乎将是所有文件.
things that have been modified in the last day, which is gonna be pretty much .
因此,这将打印
Everything ,so this is gonna print
我们今天创建的许多文件和已经存在的文件.
a lot of the files we created and files that were already there.
你还可以使用其他的标志和选项,例如大小,所有者,权限等.
You can even use other things like size, the owner, permissions, you name it.
更强大的是,"find"不仅可以查找东西,
What is even more powerful is, "find" can find stuff
它也可以在找到这些文件时执行一些操作.
but it also can do stuff when you find those files.
因此,我们可以查找所有具有"tmp"扩展名的文件,
So we could look for all the files that have a "tmp" extension,
然后,我们可以告诉"find"对于这些文件中的每一个文件,
which is a temporary extension, and then, we can tell "find" that like for every one of those files,
只需为它们执行"rm"命令.
just execute the "rm" command for them.
这将调用"rm"来处理所有这些文件.
And that will just be calling "rm" with all these files.
因此,让我们首先执行这个,然后再执行这个.
So let's first execute it without, and then we execute it with it.
看起来好像什么也没发生,这很命令行.
Again, as with the command line philosophy, it looks like nothing happened.
但是由于我们错误代码是0,所以命令都成功执行了
But since we have a "0" error code, something happened
只是一切都正确,一切都好.
just that everything went correct and everything is fine.
现在,如果我们搜索这些文件,它们就已经被删除了.
And now, if we look for these files, they aren't there anymore.
一般来说,关于Shell的另一个好处是不仅有这些工具,
Another nice thing about the Shell in general is that there are these tools,
而且人们会不断发现新的方法,
but people will keep finding new ways,
所以会有一些工具的替代品.
so alternative ways of writing these tools.
了解它非常好.
It's nice to know about it.
例如,如果你只想匹配以"tmp"结尾的内容,
So, for example "find" if you just want to match like the things that end in "tmp"
可能很难做到这一点,因为它有很长的命令.
it can be sometimes weird to do this thing, it has a long command.
所以就有了"fd"这样的东西,
There's things like "fd" for example
这是一个更短的命令,它默认使用正则表达式,
that is a shorter command that by default will use regex
甚至还能忽略搜索你的git文件.
and will ignore your gitfiles,  so you don't even search for them.
它会用不同的颜色显示代码,更好地支持Unicode编码...
It will color-code, it will have better Unicode support...
了解一些这些工具是很好的.
It's nice to know about some of these tools.
但是,再次强调的是,如果你知道这些工具的存在,
But, again, the main idea is that if you are aware that these tools exist,
你可以节省大量时间,不必做一些繁琐重复的任务.
you can save yourself a lot of time from doing kind of menial and repetitive tasks.
还有一个命令要记住,就像"find"一样.
Another command to bear in mind is like "find".
有些人可能会想,
Some of you may be wondering,
"find"可能只是实际上在遍历目录结构并寻找内容,
"find" is probably just actually going through a directory structure and looking for the things
但如果我一天要做很多"find",那怎么办?
but what if I'm doing a lot of "find"s a day?
是否更好,采用数据库方法并首先构建一个索引,
Wouldn't it be better, doing kind of a database approach and build an index first,
然后让该索引以某种方式进行更新.
and then use that index and update it in some way.
实际上,大多数Unix系统已经通过"locate"命令完成了这一点,
Well, actually most Unix systems already do it and this is through the "locate" command
而且"locate"将被用来...
and the way that the "locate" will be used...
"locate"只会查找你的文件系统中包含你想要的子字符串的路径.
it will just look for paths in your file system that have the substring that you work.
我实际上不知道它是否有效...
I actually don't know if it will work...
好的,它有效.
Okay, it worked.
让我试试像"missing-semester"这样的东西.
Let me try to do something like "missing-semester".
它会花一些时间,但它找到了所有这些文件,
You're gonna take a while but it found all these files
这些文件都在我的文件系统中某个地方,
that are somewhere in my file system
因为它已经在它们上面构建了一个索引,所以它要快得多.
and since it has built an index already on them, it's much faster.
为了使其保持更新,
And then, to keep it updated,
我们可以使用"updatedb"命令来更新此数据库.
using the "updatedb" command
这正是通过"cron"[*]运行的
that is running through "cron", to update this database.
*[Cron是一种在Unix、Linux和类Unix操作系统中用于定期运行任务的工具。\N 它允许用户指定一个或多个命令或脚本，并设置在指定时间或周期运行这些命令或脚本的方式。]
再次强调,查找文件真的很有用
Finding files, again, is really useful.
有时你实际上关心的不是文件本身,
Sometimes you're actually concerned about, not the files themselves,
而是文件的内容.
but the content of the files.
为此,可以使用我们之前看到的"grep"命令.
For that you can use the "grep" command that we have seen so far.
因此,你可以在"mcd.sh"中执行类似"grep foobar"的操作,它就在那里.
So you could do something like "grep foobar" in "mcd.sh", it's there.
如果你想要再次递归地搜索当前结构并查找更多文件,怎么办?
What if you want to, again, recursively search through the current structure and look for more files?
我们不想手动完成这项工作.
We don't want to do this manually.
我们可以使用"find"和"-exec",
We could use "find", and the "-exec",
但实际上,"grep"具有"-R"标志,它将遍历整个目录.
but actually "grep" has the "-R" flag that will go through the entire directory, here.
"example.sh"中这三行有包含"foobar"
And it's telling us that oh we have the "foobar" line in "example.sh"
另外还有两个文件也含有"foobar"
at these three places and in this other two places in foobar.
这非常方便.
This can be really convenient.
主要用例是,
Mainly, kind of the use case for this is
你知道你已经用某种编程语言编写了一些代码,
you know you have written some code in some programming language,
并且知道它在你的文件系统的某个地方,
and you know it's somewhere in your file system
但你实际上不知道在哪里.
but you actually don't know.
你就可以快速搜索.
But you can actually quickly search.
例如,我可以在"scratch"文件夹中
So for example, I can quickly search for all the Python files
快速搜索导入了"requests"库的所有Python文件.
that I have in my scratch folder where I used the request library.
如果我运行这个命令,它会搜索所有这些文件,
And if I run this, it's giving me through all these files, exactly in
并精确地给出在哪一行找到了它.
what line it has been found.
这里,我没有使用"grep",(当然这也是可以的)
And here instead of using "grep", which is fine, you could also do this,
而是使用了"ripgrep",它与"grep"的想法有点相同,
I'm using "ripgrep", which is kind of the same idea
但是"ripgrep"更好康,比如彩色编码或文件处理等.
but again trying to bring some more niceties like color coding or file processing and other things.
它也支持unicode.
It think it has, also, unicode support.
但是你不必担心他因为这些功能而速度会慢,它查找速度也很快.
It's also pretty fast so you are not paying like a trade-off on this being slower
还有许多有用的标志.
and there's a lot of useful flags.
你可以说,哦,我实际上想获得这些结果周围的一些上下文.
You can say, oh, I actually want to get some context around those results.
因此,你可以看到导入所在的位置
So I want to get like five lines of context around that,
并查看周围的代码.
so you can see where that import lives and see code around it.
在导入中,这并不是真正有用的,
Here in the import it's not really useful
但是如果你正在寻找使用该函数的位置,
but like if you're looking for where you use the function, for example,
那么它将非常方便.
It will be very handy.
我们还可以做其他事情,例如在这里.
We can also do things like we can search, for example here,.
更高级的用法,我们可以说,"-u"是为了不忽略隐藏文件,
A more advanced use, we can say, "-u" is for don't ignore hidden files,
有时你想忽略隐藏文件,
sometimes you want to be ignoring hidden files,
除非你要搜索默认隐藏的配置文件.
except if you want to search config files, that are by default hidden.
然后,我们不是打印匹配项,
Then, instead of printing the matches,
而是要求执行一些可能很难使用"grep"实现的操作
we're asking to do something that would be kind of hard, I think,to do with "grep", out of my head,
比如"我希望你打印出所有不匹配给定模式的文件",
which is I want you to print all the files that don't match the pattern I'm giving you,
这可能是一个奇怪的要求,但请你们继续看...
which may be a weird thing to ask here but then we keep going...
这里的模式是一个正则表达式,
And this pattern here is a small regex
它表示在行的开头有一个"#"和一个"!",这是一个shebang.
which is saying at the beginning of the line I have a "#" and a "!", and that's a shebang.
这样,我们在这里搜索所有没有shebang的文件,
Like that, we're searching here for all the files that don't have a shebang
然后在这里给它一个"-t sh"表示只查找"sh"文件,
and then we're giving it, here, a "-t sh" to only look for "sh" files,
因为你的Python或文本文件可能没有shebang也没问题.
because maybe all your Python or text files are fine without a shebang.
这里告诉我们,"哦,mcd.sh显然缺少一个shebang",
And here it's telling us "oh, 'mcd.sh' is obviously missing a shebang"
我们甚至可以...
We can even...
它有一些不错的标志,例如如果我们包括"--stats"标志,
It has like some nice flags, so for example if we include the "--stats" flag
它将得到所有这些结果,
it will get all these results
它还会告诉我们它所搜索的所有内容的信息.
but it will also tell us information about all the things that it searched.
例如,找到的匹配次数、行数、搜索的文件、
For example, the number of matches that it found, the lines, the file searched,
打印的字节数等等.
the bytes that it printed, etc.
与"fd"类似,它有时候不是很好用
Similar as with "fd", sometimes it's not as useful
有时候特定的工具并不是很有用,就跟"ripgrep"一样,
using one specific tool or another and in fact, as "ripgrep",
还有像"ack"这样的工具是最初编写的"grep"替代工具.
there are several other tools, like "ack", you know, is kind of the original "grep" alternative that was written.
然后是另一个工具"ag".
Then the silver searcher, "ag", was another one...
它们都可以相互替换,
and they're all pretty much interchangeable
所以也许你所在的系统有其中一个而没有另一个,
so maybe you're at a system that has one and not the other,
你只要知道你可以使用这些非常好用的工具.
just knowing that you can use these things with these tools can be fairly useful.
最后,我想谈谈如何查找你已经使用过的命令,不是找文件或代码.
Lastly, I want to cover how you go about, not finding files or code,
就是你如何找到你已经使用过的命令.
but how you go about finding commands that you already some time figured out.
第一种,显然的方法就是使用"↑",
The first, obvious way is just using the up arrow,
慢慢浏览你的历史记录,寻找这些匹配项.
and slowly going through all your history, looking for these matches.
这实际上并不是很高效,你可能已经猜到了.
This is actually not very efficient, as you probably guessed.
因此,bash有更轻松的方法来做这件事.
So the bash has ways to do this more easily.
有一个history命令,会打印出你的历史记录.
There is the "history" command, that will print your history.
这里我在zsh中,它只打印出一部分历史记录,
Here I'm in zsh and it only prints some of my history,
但如果我说,我想要你从一切开始打印,
but if I say, I want you to print everything from the beginning of time,
它将从这个历史记录的开始打印一切.
it will print everything from the beginning of whatever this history is.
由于这是很多结果,也许我们关心的是
And since this is a lot of results, maybe we care about the ones
我们使用"convert"命令
where we use the "convert" command
使其从某种文件类型转换为另一种文件类型.
to go from some type of file to some other type of file.
一些图片....呃
Some image, sorry.
然后,我们获得了所有与该子字符串匹配的结果.
Then, we're getting all these results here, about all the ones that match this substring.
几乎所有的shell默认都会将"Ctrl+R"这个键绑定为反向搜索.
Even more, pretty much all Shells by default will link "Ctrl+R", the keybinding, to do backward search.
这里我们有一个反向搜索,我们可以输入"convert",
Here we have backward search, where we can type "convert"
它会找到我们刚输入的命令.
and it's finding the command that we just typed.
如果我们一直按"Ctrl+R",
And if we just keep hitting "Ctrl+R",
它会浏览这些匹配项,让我们在原地重新执行.
it will kind of go through these matches and it will let re-execute it in place.
另外一件你可以做的与此相关的事情,
Another thing that you can do, related to that,
是你可以使用这个非常棒的工具叫做"fzf",
is you can use this really nifty tool called "fzf",
"fzf"是一个模糊查找器,
which is like a fuzzy finder, like it will let you...
它可以让你进行交互式的"grep".
It will let you do kind of like an interactive "grep".
例如,我们可以执行cat example.sh,
We could do for example this, where we can cat our "example.sh" command,
它将打印到标准输出,
that will print print to the standard output,
并将其传递到"fzf"中.
and then we can pipe it through "fzf".
它只是获取所有的行,
It's just getting all the lines
然后我们可以交互式地查找我们关心的字符串.
and then we can interactively look for the string that we care about.
"fzf"的好处是,
And the nice thing about fzf is that,
如果你启用了默认绑定,它会绑定到你的"Ctrl+R",
if you enable the default bindings, it will bind to your "Ctrl+R" Shell execution
现在你可以快速交互式地在历史记录中查找
and now you can quickly and dynamically like look for
所有你尝试转换"favicon"的命令.
all the times you try to convert a favicon in your history.
它还可以模糊匹配,.
And it's also like fuzzy matching,
而默认情况下"grep"或这些工具,
whereas like by default in "grep" or these things
需要写一个正则表达式来进行匹配.
you have to write a regex or some expression that will match within here.
而这里我只是输入"convert"和"favi",
Here I'm just typing "convert" and "favi"
它尝试做出最佳扫描,在它的输入中进行匹配.
and it's just trying to do the best scan, doing the match in the lines it has.
最后,一个你可能已经见过的工具,
Lastly, a tool that probably you have already seen,
我用它来避免重新输入这些非常长的命令,
that I've been using for not retyping these extremely long commands
它叫做"历史子字符串搜索",
is this "history substring search",
当我在shell中输入时,
where as I type in my Shell,
Fish没提到这个概念,我认为最初是由zsh引入的,
both Fish fail to mention but zsh, which I think originally introduced this concept
而且zsh有一个很好的实现,我认为最初是由它引入的,
and then zsh has a really nice implementation
它让你在键入命令时,
What it'll let you do is as you type the command,
动态地在历史记录中搜索具有相同前缀的相同命令,
it will dynamically like search back in your history to the same command that has a common prefix,
然后,如果你...
and then, if you...
它会随着匹配列表停止工作而改变,然后当你按"→"时,
it will change as the match list stops working and then as you do the right arrow.
你可以选择那个命令,然后重新执行它.
you can select that command and then re-execute it.
我们已经看到了一些东西...
We've seen a bunch of stuff...
我想我还有几分钟的时间,
I think I have a few minutes left
所以我要介绍一些快速目录列表和目录导航的工具.
so I'm going to cover a couple of tools to do \N kind of really quick directory listing and directory navigation.
你总是可以使用"-R"来递归地列出某个目录结构,
So you can always use the "-R" to recursively list some directory structure,
但这可能不是最优的,这不是很好理解.
but that can be suboptimal, I cannot really make sense of this easily.
有一个叫做"tree"的工具,它更友好地打印目录结构,
There's tool called "tree" that will be the much more friendly form of printing all the stuff,
它也会根据不同的类型进行着色...
it will also color code based on...
例如,这里的"foo"是蓝色的,因为它是一个目录,
here for example "foo" is blue because it's a directory
这个是红色的,因为它有执行权限.
and this is red because it has execute permissions.
但我们可以做得更好.
But we can go even further than that.
有一些很好的工具,
There's really nice tools
比如最近出现的一个叫做"broot"的工具,它可以做同样的事情,
like a recent one called "broot" that will do the same thing
但是在这里,不像列出每一个单独的文件,
but here for example instead of doing this thing of listing every single file,
例如在"bar"中,我们有这些"a"到"j"的文件,
for example in bar we have these "a" through "j" files,
它会说"噢,还有更多,这里就不列举了".
it will say "oh there are more, unlisted here".
我实际上可以开始输入,它会再次匹配到那些存在的文件,
I can actually start typing and it will again facily match to the files that are there
我可以快速选择它们并浏览它们.
and I can quickly select them and navigate through them.
因此,了解这些事情很重要.
So, again, it's good to know that these things exist
这样你就不会浪费大量时间去寻找这些文件.
so you don't lose a large amount of time going for these files.
还有,我也安装了一些你也许想要的工具,
There are also, I think I have it installed also something more similar to what you would expect your OS to have,
比如Nautilus或者其中一个Mac Finder,
like Nautilus or one of the Mac finders
它们有一个交互式的界面,你可以使用箭头快速浏览.
that have like an interactive input where you can just use your navigation arrows and quickly explore.
你可能觉得花里胡哨,
It might be overkill
但你会惊讶地发现,
but you'll be surprised
通过浏览某个目录结构,你可以很快地理解它.
how quickly you can make sense of some directory structure by just navigating through it.
几乎所有这些工具去看看选项,都可以让你编辑、复制文件……
And pretty much all of these tools will let you edit, copy files...\N if you just look for the options for them.
最后的补充内容有点复杂.
The last addendum is kind of going places.
我们有"cd","cd"很好用,它会让你到达很多地方.
We have "cd", and "cd" is nice, it will get you to a lot of places.
但是如果你可以快速到达一些地方,还有更方便的方法.
But it's pretty handy if you can like quickly go places,
具体地说,就是
you are...
你最近或经常去的地方
either you have been to recently or that you go frequently.
你可以用很多种方式做到这一点,
And you can do this in many ways there's probably you can start thinking,
我可以做书签,我可以……
oh I can make bookmarks, I can make...
我可以在shell中创建别名,我们以后会介绍到这个问题,
I can make aliases in the Shell, that we will cover at some point,
可以创建符号链接……
symlinks...
但是此时,程序员已经构建了这些工具,
But at this point ,programmers have like built all these tools,
所以程序员已经找到了一个非常好的方法来做到这一点.
so programmers have already figured out a really nice way of doing this.
其中一种方法是使用所谓的"autojump",
One way of doing this is using what is called "auto jump",
我想这里没有加载……
which I think is not loaded here...
不过,别担心.
Okay, don't worry.
我将在命令行环境中介绍它.
I will cover it in the command line environment.
我想这是因为我禁用了"Ctrl+R",
I think it's because I disabled the "Ctrl+R"
这也影响了脚本的其他部分.
and that also affected other parts of the script.
如果有任何与此相关的问题,
I think at this point if anyone has any questions that are related to this,
如果有任何不清楚的地方,我很乐意回答.
I'll be more than happy to answer them,  if anything was left unclear.
如果没有的话,我们编写了一堆关于这些工具的练习,
Otherwise, there's a bunch of exercises that we wrote, kind of touching on these topics
我们鼓励你尝试解决它们,并在办公时间前来,
and we encourage you to try them and come to office hours,
我们可以帮助你弄清如何做这些事情,
where we can help you figure out how to do them,
或者一些你不清楚的bash技巧.
or some like bash quirks that are not clear.